Ashish Surana

SOFTWARE ENGINEER (FRONTEND)

Düsseldorf, Germany

📞 (+91) 978 487 8727 | 🖂 ashishsurana.in@gmail.com | 🏕 ashishsurana.in | 🗘 ashishsurana | in ashishsurana

Summary _____

Creative and self-starting software engineer with 5+ years of experience in Front-end Engineering. The challenges of scaling and improving User Interface is my motivation. I am always driven to write clean, composable & testable code.

Skills _

Proficiency JavaScript, Functional programming

Libraries - React, Redux

Frameworks - Electron, Express, Node.js, Next.js

Typed Systems - Typescript, Flow

Also Familiar with GraphQL, Amazon Web Services, Apollo, Design Documents

Packaging - webpack, Docker

Automation - Gitlab CI

Release Management - npm & Semver, A/B Testing

Certifications Red Hat Certified Engineer (RHCE)

Experience _____

Trivago N VSOFTWARE ENGINEER (JAVASCRIPT)

Düsseldorf, Germany

November 2020 - PRESENT

- About trivago trivago is a global hotel search platform. The Product consist of a meta search and a booking engine. And my roles were as follows:
- Ownership of Front end part of express-booking, Responsibilities including preparing design document, tackling tech-debt, improving processes
- Actively involved in cross team communication with Designers, Product owners, other Engineers to take the product forward with matching business KPIs.
- Technologies React, Node.js, symphony, Server Side Rendering

Innovaccer Analytics

Noida, India

January 2018 - November

2020

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER - I

- About Innovaccer Innovaccer is a **healthcare** data activation platform for care management. The Product consist of a Micro Front-end application and my roles were as follows:
- Ownership of development and releasing two modules in React using Redux and styled components
- Technologies React, AngularJs, Next.js, Express, Server Side Rendering

AadhaarApi.com

Pune, India

JAVASCRIPT ENGINEER Aug. 2017 - Jan. 2018

• About AdhaarAPI - Aadhaar is the database containing biometrics **1.3 Billion Indians** and AadhaarAPI is a product to leverage the power by developing SDKs over it. I worked on the back-end for the "**Know Your Customer** (EKYC)" using aadhaar APIs

- Successfully delivered Dashboard from scratch and developed efficient **REST API**s for improving workflows
- Technologies React, Redux, Server Side Rendering, Node.js, Postgres, AWS

JULY 10, 2022 ASHISH SURANA · RESUME

Open Source _____

Verdaccio

- A Open Source lightweight private npm proxy registry. My contribution was solving bugs, improving test cases, and discussing the feature developments
- Technologies: Nodejs, React, npm, Webpack, Enzyme
- Link: github.com/verdaccio/verdaccio

Projects _____

trivago Express Booking

- Express booking, a booking engine that helps users and advertisers to process their room reservations.
- It's a legacy application of which I took the ownership when I joined the team. I with my team managed to migrate it to react while making sure the KPIs are intact.

Datashop Engine (Innovaccer)

- Datashop-Engine, a **Back-end for Front-end** framework developed to take care of the connection points between existing popular frameworks like Angular, React based applications.
- Everything in Datashop is a package and **Micro-Frontend** architecture allows developers to extend product with custom functionality by creating their own package and publish independently.

Incore (Innovaccer)

- This App is the part of datashop and tightly coupled with core framework. This module take care of all **Role-based**Access Control across the Product
- This module is a User Management and Audit Logs Application for product
- Technologies : React, Redux, AngularJs, Express

Education

Rajasthan Technical University

Kota, India

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY (COMPUTER SCIENCE ENGINEERING)

June 2017

Vivekananda Kendra Vidyalaya (CBSE)

Bhilwara, India

HIGHER SECONDARY EDUCATION

May 2013

Awards & Participations _____

Hackathon Winner

trivago, Germany

MARCH, 2022

• We won the internal Hackathon in which Challenge was to ship a feature in finding a deal. Later it was accepted after A/B Test.

Star Performer Award

Innovaccer, India

JULY, 2019

• I was awarded as a Star Performer of Quarter two, 2019 for extra ordinary performance in the field of Product Engineering.